// import shuffleArray from "../helpers/shuffleArray.js";

// import { getRandomItem } from "../helpers/shuffleAnswer.js";
// const getRandomItem = (array) =>
//   array[Math.floor(Math.random() * array.length)];

export const HarryPotterQuestions = [
  {
    question: "What is the name of Harry Potter's pet owl?",
    options: ["Hedwig", "Fawkes", "Crookshanks", "Scabbers"],
    correctAnswer: "Hedwig",
  },
  {
    question: "Who teaches Potions in Harry's first year at Hogwarts?",
    options: [
      "Severus Snape",
      "Minerva McGonagall",
      "Horace Slughorn",
      "Gilderoy Lockhart",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What magical creature is known for guarding the wizarding bank, Gringotts?",
    options: ["Goblin", "Elf", "Centaur", "Troll"],
    correctAnswer: "Goblin",
  },
  {
    question: "Which house at Hogwarts is known for bravery?",
    options: ["Hufflepuff", "Gryffindor", "Ravenclaw", "Slytherin"],
    correctAnswer: "Gryffindor",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the headmaster of Hogwarts during Harry's first year?",
    options: [
      "Albus Dumbledore",
      "Severus Snape",
      "Minerva McGonagall",
      "Gellert Grindelwald",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Albus Dumbledore",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Hermione's cat?",
    options: ["Crookshanks", "Hedwig", "Pygmy Puff", "Fawkes"],
    correctAnswer: "Crookshanks",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to disarm an opponent?",
    options: ["Expelliarmus", "Stupefy", "Lumos", "Aguamenti"],
    correctAnswer: "Expelliarmus",
  },
  {
    question: "Which item allows wizards to travel through time?",
    options: ["Time-Turner", "Portkey", "Broomstick", "Invisibility Cloak"],
    correctAnswer: "Time-Turner",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the Weasley family's house?",
    options: [
      "Hogwarts",
      "The Burrow",
      "Malfoy Manor",
      "Number 4 Privet Drive",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Burrow",
  },
  {
    question: "What creature pulls the carriages to Hogwarts?",
    options: ["Thestrals", "Hippogriffs", "Unicorns", "Banshees"],
    correctAnswer: "Thestrals",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the dark wizard who killed Harry's parents?",
    options: [
      "Lord Voldemort",
      "Lucius Malfoy",
      "Bellatrix Lestrange",
      "Peter Pettigrew",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lord Voldemort",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to create a Patronus?",
    options: ["Expecto Patronum", "Avada Kedavra", "Protego", "Riddikulus"],
    correctAnswer: "Expecto Patronum",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Ron's pet rat?",
    options: ["Scabbers", "Trevor", "Hedwig", "Crookshanks"],
    correctAnswer: "Scabbers",
  },
  {
    question: "Which Quidditch position does Harry play?",
    options: ["Seeker", "Keeper", "Chaser", "Beater"],
    correctAnswer: "Seeker",
  },
  {
    question: "What potion is known as the Elixir of Life?",
    options: [
      "Felix Felicis",
      "Polyjuice Potion",
      "Amortentia",
      "The Philosopher's Stone",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Philosopher's Stone",
  },
  {
    question: "Who kills Dumbledore?",
    options: [
      "Severus Snape",
      "Bellatrix Lestrange",
      "Draco Malfoy",
      "Voldemort",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the Weasley twins' shop?",
    options: [
      "Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes",
      "Honeydukes",
      "Zonko's",
      "The Quibbler",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes",
  },
  {
    question: "Which spell is used to repel Dementors?",
    options: ["Expecto Patronum", "Stupefy", "Avada Kedavra", "Lumos"],
    correctAnswer: "Expecto Patronum",
  },
  {
    question: "Who becomes the Minister of Magic at the end of the series?",
    options: [
      "Kingsley Shacklebolt",
      "Cornelius Fudge",
      "Rufus Scrimgeour",
      "Arthur Weasley",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Kingsley Shacklebolt",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the potion that grants luck?",
    options: ["Felix Felicis", "Polyjuice Potion", "Amortentia", "Veritaserum"],
    correctAnswer: "Felix Felicis",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is Harry's godfather?",
    options: [
      "Sirius Black",
      "Remus Lupin",
      "Albus Dumbledore",
      "Severus Snape",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Sirius Black",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the school that Harry attends?",
    options: [
      "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry",
      "Beauxbatons Academy",
      "Durmstrang Institute",
      "Ilvermorny School",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the spell 'Aguamenti' do?",
    options: [
      "Creates water",
      "Ignites fire",
      "Transfigures objects",
      "Levitation",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Creates water",
  },
  {
    question: "What magical object does Harry inherit from Sirius?",
    options: ["Invisibility Cloak", "Broomstick", "Firebolt", "Marauder's Map"],
    correctAnswer: "Firebolt",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the Half-Blood Prince?",
    options: [
      "Severus Snape",
      "Tom Riddle",
      "Albus Dumbledore",
      "Lucius Malfoy",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape",
  },
  {
    question: "What creature can transform into the worst fear of a person?",
    options: ["Boggart", "Thestral", "Acromantula", "Dementor"],
    correctAnswer: "Boggart",
  },
  {
    question: "Which spell is used to heal minor injuries?",
    options: ["Episkey", "Stupefy", "Sectumsempra", "Rictusempra"],
    correctAnswer: "Episkey",
  },
  {
    question: "What magical item can transport you anywhere?",
    options: ["Portkey", "Broomstick", "Apparition", "Time-Turner"],
    correctAnswer: "Portkey",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the core of Harry's wand?",
    options: [
      "Phoenix feather",
      "Unicorn hair",
      "Dragon heartstring",
      "Thestral tail hair",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Phoenix feather",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the village near Hogwarts?",
    options: [
      "Hogsmeade",
      "Diagon Alley",
      "Little Whinging",
      "Godric's Hollow",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hogsmeade",
  },
  {
    question: "Which ghost haunts Gryffindor House?",
    options: [
      "Nearly Headless Nick",
      "The Grey Lady",
      "The Bloody Baron",
      "Moaning Myrtle",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Nearly Headless Nick",
  },
  {
    question: "What is Ron's favorite food?",
    options: [
      "Chocolate frogs",
      "Pumpkin pasties",
      "Treacle tart",
      "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Treacle tart",
  },
  {
    question: "What item is needed to enter the Chamber of Secrets?",
    options: ["Parseltongue", "A special key", "A password", "A magical map"],
    correctAnswer: "Parseltongue",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who teaches Defense Against the Dark Arts in Harry's third year?",
    options: [
      "Remus Lupin",
      "Gilderoy Lockhart",
      "Dolores Umbridge",
      "Severus Snape",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Remus Lupin",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the first Harry Potter book?",
    options: [
      "Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone",
      "Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets",
      "Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban",
      "Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the train that takes students to Hogwarts?",
    options: [
      "Hogwarts Express",
      "Hogwarts Train",
      "Magical Express",
      "Wizarding Express",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hogwarts Express",
  },
  {
    question: "What is Voldemort's real name?",
    options: ["Tom Riddle", "Severus Snape", "Lucius Malfoy", "Draco Malfoy"],
    correctAnswer: "Tom Riddle",
  },
  {
    question: "What type of creature is Dobby?",
    options: ["House-elf", "Goblin", "Hippogriff", "Banshee"],
    correctAnswer: "House-elf",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to stun an opponent?",
    options: ["Stupefy", "Expelliarmus", "Avada Kedavra", "Riddikulus"],
    correctAnswer: "Stupefy",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the head of Slytherin House?",
    options: [
      "Severus Snape",
      "Horace Slughorn",
      "Lucius Malfoy",
      "Draco Malfoy",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Severus Snape",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the room where the Triwizard Tournament's tasks take place?",
    options: [
      "The Great Hall",
      "The Quidditch Pitch",
      "The Forbidden Forest",
      "The Triwizard Arena",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Triwizard Arena",
  },
  {
    question: "What magical object reveals the true nature of a person?",
    options: [
      "Mirror of Erised",
      "The Sorting Hat",
      "The Pensieve",
      "The Marauder's Map",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mirror of Erised",
  },
  {
    question: "What creature is known for its ability to turn invisible?",
    options: ["Niffler", "Hippogriff", "Basilisk", "Acromantula"],
    correctAnswer: "Niffler",
  },
  {
    question: "Which spell is used to unlock doors?",
    options: ["Alohomora", "Expelliarmus", "Colloportus", "Lumos"],
    correctAnswer: "Alohomora",
  },
  {
    question: "What does Hermione use to brew Polyjuice Potion?",
    options: ["A cauldron", "A potion book", "Her wand", "A spell"],
    correctAnswer: "A cauldron",
  },
  {
    question: "What magical plant is used to treat injuries?",
    options: ["Mandrake", "Wolfsbane", "Belladonna", "Devil's Snare"],
    correctAnswer: "Mandrake",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the ghost of Slytherin House?",
    options: [
      "The Bloody Baron",
      "Nearly Headless Nick",
      "The Grey Lady",
      "Moaning Myrtle",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "The Bloody Baron",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to conjure light?",
    options: ["Lumos", "Nox", "Accio", "Incendio"],
    correctAnswer: "Lumos",
  },
  {
    question: "Who helps Harry with the Triwizard Tournament tasks?",
    options: [
      "Hermione Granger",
      "Ron Weasley",
      "Albus Dumbledore",
      "Cedric Diggory",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Hermione Granger",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Hagrid's giant pet spider?",
    options: ["Aragog", "Buckbeak", "Fluffy", "Norbert"],
    correctAnswer: "Aragog",
  },
  {
    question: "What type of creature is Buckbeak?",
    options: ["Hippogriff", "Thestral", "Dragon", "Unicorn"],
    correctAnswer: "Hippogriff",
  },
  {
    question: "What does Harry receive for his 11th birthday?",
    options: ["Letter from Hogwarts", "A broomstick", "A pet owl", "A wand"],
    correctAnswer: "Letter from Hogwarts",
  },
  {
    question: "Which spell creates a protective shield?",
    options: ["Protego", "Avada Kedavra", "Expelliarmus", "Stupefy"],
    correctAnswer: "Protego",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Harry's first broomstick?",
    options: ["Nimbus 2000", "Firebolt", "Comet 260", "Cleansweep 7"],
    correctAnswer: "Nimbus 2000",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is known as the 'Chosen One'?",
    options: [
      "Harry Potter",
      "Neville Longbottom",
      "Albus Dumbledore",
      "Ron Weasley",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Harry Potter",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What magical creature does Harry encounter in the Forbidden Forest?",
    options: ["Unicorn", "Basilisk", "Hippogriff", "Acromantula"],
    correctAnswer: "Unicorn",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to make someone tell the truth?",
    options: ["Veritaserum", "Obliviate", "Imperio", "Crucio"],
    correctAnswer: "Veritaserum",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the last surviving member of the Black family?",
    options: [
      "Sirius Black",
      "Bellatrix Lestrange",
      "Regulus Black",
      "Andromeda Tonks",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Andromeda Tonks",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the shop where Harry buys his wand?",
    options: [
      "Ollivanders",
      "Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes",
      "Honeydukes",
      "Flourish and Blotts",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ollivanders",
  },
  {
    question: "What spell is used to levitate objects?",
    options: ["Wingardium Leviosa", "Levioso", "Accio", "Mobilicorpus"],
    correctAnswer: "Wingardium Leviosa",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of Harry's first Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher?",
    options: [
      "Quirinus Quirrell",
      "Gilderoy Lockhart",
      "Remus Lupin",
      "Dolores Umbridge",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Quirinus Quirrell",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the potion that allows a person to transform into someone else?",
    options: ["Polyjuice Potion", "Amortentia", "Felix Felicis", "Veritaserum"],
    correctAnswer: "Polyjuice Potion",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the house-elf who serves the Malfoy family?",
    options: ["Dobby", "Winky", "Kreacher", "Hokey"],
    correctAnswer: "Kreacher",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the magical tournament that takes place in *Goblet of Fire*?",
    options: [
      "Triwizard Tournament",
      "Wizengamot Trials",
      "Dueling Club",
      "Battle of Hogwarts",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Triwizard Tournament",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not one of Voldemort's Horcruxes?",
    options: ["Nagini", "The diary", "The diadem", "The Marauder's Map"],
    correctAnswer: "The Marauder's Map",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the spell used to summon objects?",
    options: ["Accio", "Summon", "Lumos", "Expelliarmus"],
    correctAnswer: "Accio",
  },
  {
    question: "Who did Harry first meet when he arrived at Hogwarts?",
    options: [
      "Ron Weasley",
      "Hermione Granger",
      "Draco Malfoy",
      "Neville Longbottom",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ron Weasley",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the magical school in France?",
    options: ["Beauxbatons", "Durmstrang", "Ilvermorny", "Hogwarts"],
    correctAnswer: "Beauxbatons",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What creature is known for being able to turn to stone when looked at?",
    options: ["Basilisk", "Gorgon", "Acromantula", "Chimera"],
    correctAnswer: "Basilisk",
  },
  {
    question: "What does Hermione use to turn into a cat?",
    options: [
      "Polyjuice Potion",
      "Transfiguration Spell",
      "Animagus Form",
      "Invisibility Cloak",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Polyjuice Potion",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the Sorting Hat use to decide which house a student belongs to?",
    options: [
      "Character traits",
      "Family background",
      "Magical abilities",
      "Test scores",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Character traits",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Hagrid's three-headed dog?",
    options: ["Fluffy", "Fang", "Norbert", "Aragog"],
    correctAnswer: "Fluffy",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the ghost of Gryffindor House?",
    options: [
      "Nearly Headless Nick",
      "The Grey Lady",
      "Moaning Myrtle",
      "The Bloody Baron",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Nearly Headless Nick",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is Harry's main rival in Quidditch?",
    options: ["Draco Malfoy", "Cedric Diggory", "Viktor Krum", "Oliver Wood"],
    correctAnswer: "Draco Malfoy",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the spell that makes objects fly?",
    options: ["Wingardium Leviosa", "Levioso", "Accio", "Aguamenti"],
    correctAnswer: "Wingardium Leviosa",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the last book in the Harry Potter series?",
    options: [
      "Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows",
      "Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince",
      "Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire",
      "Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Voldemort's snake?",
    options: ["Nagini", "Aragog", "Fang", "Basilisk"],
    correctAnswer: "Nagini",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the Marauder's Map show?",
    options: [
      "People's locations",
      "Secrets of Hogwarts",
      "Magical creatures",
      "Hidden passages",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "People's locations",
  },
  {
    question: "Who are the original Marauders?",
    options: [
      "James Potter, Sirius Black, Remus Lupin, Peter Pettigrew",
      "Harry Potter, Ron Weasley, Hermione Granger",
      "Albus Dumbledore, Severus Snape, Gellert Grindelwald",
      "Tom Riddle, Bellatrix Lestrange, Lucius Malfoy",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "James Potter, Sirius Black, Remus Lupin, Peter Pettigrew",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the potion that creates a strong attraction?",
    options: ["Amortentia", "Felix Felicis", "Polyjuice Potion", "Veritaserum"],
    correctAnswer: "Amortentia",
  },
  {
    question: "Who was the first person to be killed by Voldemort?",
    options: [
      "Lily Potter",
      "James Potter",
      "Sirius Black",
      "Albus Dumbledore",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Lily Potter",
  },
];

export default HarryPotterQuestions;
